Guide to the Peter Palmquist Cased Photographs Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Images by Identified Photographers, Series I; (161 items)
  - CALIFORNIA PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Vance, Robert H., 1825-1876
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 11, Folder 110)
        Full plain pigskin case imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 12, Folder 111)
        Quarter-plate daguerreotype; modern seal
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, identified as William Hartwell, 1853-circa 1855 (Box 12, Folder 112)
        Full leather case with Birds and Flower Vase motif (Rinhart #91); imprint on velvet pad of case, "R. H. VANCE'S / PREMIUM DAGUERREAN GALLERIES / SAN FRANCISCO / SACRAMENTO / MARYSVILLE"
  - ALABAMA PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Badgley
      Centre
      - Tintype in a case, of an elderly man, identified as C. S. Shields, 1859 (Box 12, Folder 113)
        Sixth-plate tintype, modern seal
        Pencil inscription under image, "C. S. Shields, / 56 years old / 1859 / Taken by / Prof. Badgley, / at Centre / Ala. / Cost - $3.00"
  - IOWA PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Fetter, Harvey G.
      Peru
      - Tintype in a case, of a woman, circa 1858-61 (Box 12, Folder 114)
        Half-plate hand-tinted tintype
        Blindstamp lower edge, "FETTER, PERU, IA"
        Full papier-mache case
    - Swan
      Birmingham
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a girl and a man, 1853 Jul 14 (Box 12, Folder 115)
        Ink inscription on pad, "Taken July the 14 / 1853 By Mr. Swan / Birmingham, Iowa"
  - KENTUCKY PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Harris, Theodore
      Louisville
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1855-60 (Box 12, Folder 116)
        Full brown leather case; imprint on velvet pad of case: "THEO. HARRIS / ARTIST/ LOUISVILLE, KY."
  - MASSACHUSETTS PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Allen, Charles V. (b. 1828)
      Boston
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, 1854-56 (Box 12, Folder 117)
        Ninth-plate daguerreotype; modern seal
        Blindstamp on mat, "WINDER COR. W. ROW & COURT CIN. O."
        Full leather case; blindstamp on velvet pad of case, "C.V. ALLEN / DAGUERREOTYPEST (sic.) / 238 WASHINGTON ST."
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, 1854-56 (Box 12, Folder 118)
        Ninth-plate daguerreotype; original seal
        Full leather case with floral motif and geometric scrolling; blindstamp on velvet pad of case, "C.V. ALLEN / DAGUERREOTYPEST (sic.) / 238 WASHINGTON ST."
    - Daniels, Austin F.
      Worcester
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a boy, circa 1860 (Box 12, Folder 119)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo; original seal
        Blindstamp lower right on mat, "A.F. DANIELS"; blindstamp lower left on mat, "CUTTING'S PATENT / JULY 4 & 11 1854"
        Full papier-mache case with the Tangent Circle motif (Rinhart #195)
    - Hale, Luther Holman (1823-1885)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, possibly husband of Cordelia W. Lewis, 1845-56 (Box 12, Folder 120)
        Full leather case with floral bouquet motif; imprint on velvet pad of case, "L.H. HALE ARTIST. / 109 / WASHINGTON ST. / BOSTON"
        Possible companion image to Item 121
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, identified as Cordelia W. Lewis, 1845-56 (Box 13, Folder 121)
        Inscription on note accompanying image, "Cordelia W. Lewis"
        Possible companion image to Item 120
    - Hamilton, George D.
      - Daguerreotype in half case of a woman, 1852-60 (Box 13, Folder 122)
        Blindstamp in lower right corner on mat, "G. D. HAMILTON / 63 COURT ST"
    - Hathaway, William
      New Bedford
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl posed reclining on a couch, 1857-58 (Box 13, Folder 123)
        Quarter-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing in relievo; metal backing plate; original seal.
        Full brown thermoplastic case with Alone at the Rendezvous motif (Krainik #31); printed on paper lining, "A.P. CRITCHLOW & CO., / Manufacturers of / Daguerreotype Cases. / A.P.C. & CO. / Are the Original Inventors of / the Composition for the Union Case, / (so called,) including all the various shades / of color and fineness of texture pecu- / liar to their manufacture and of the / EMBRACING RIVETED HINGES, thus / securing them from breaking out as / do others that are inserted / with or without a / metal brace. / Hinge Patented / OCT. 14, 1856." Added on paper lining in ink, "And / April 21, 1857"; circular inked stamp on paper case backing label, "CUTTING'S PATENT. / JULY / 4TH & 11TH, 1854. / WM. HATHAWAY / AMBROTYPE ARTIST"
    - Hawes, Charles E.
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl, 1859 (Box 13, Folder 124)
        Full brown thermoplastic octagon case with Geometric/Scroll motif (Krainik #360)
    - Maxham, Benjamin D.
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, identified as William K. Ware, 1855-58 (Box 13, Folder 125)
        Ninth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with metal backing; no seal
        Paper label behind image with inscription, "Will K. Ware"
        Blindstamp under image on mat, "B.D. MAXHAM"
        Full papier-mache case with geometric motif; imprint on velvet pad, "MAXHAM'S / 50c / AMBROTYPES / HARRINGTON / COR."
    - Shew, William (1820-1903)
      See also: Items 43-61
      - Case cover, circa 1845-1850 (Box 13, Folder 126)
        Label in case cover, "MADE BY / WILLIAM SHEW / CORNER OF COURT & HOWARD STS. / BOSTON"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, identified as Moses Lyman, circa 1845-50 (Box 13, Folder 127)
        Full brown leather case with Curved Octagon with Scroll, Center motif (Rinhart #219); printed on paper lining, "MADE BY / WILLIAM SHEW, / CORNER OF COURT & HOWARD STS. / BOSTON"
        Paper strip with inscription, "Moses Lyman" affixed to silk pad
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1844-50 (Box 13, Folder 128)
        Full leather case with the Delicate Roses, Variant motif (Rinhart #123); printed on paper lining, "WM. SHEW / MINIATURE CASE MAKER, / AND DEALER IN / Daguerreotype Materials / 123 Washington Street, / BOSTON"; pencil notation on paper lining, "N.R. Allen / 1334. / Sharp."
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1844-50 (Box 13, Folder 129)
        Full brown leather case in Curved Octagon with Scroll, Center motif (Rinhart #219); printed on paper lining, "WM. SHEW, / Miniature Casemaker, / And Dealer in / Plates, Lockets, Chemicals, and / German & American Cameras, / Corner of Court and Howard Sts. / BOSTON."
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1844-50 (Box 13, Folder 130)
        Full leather case with The Delicate Roses, Variant motif (Rinhart #123); printed on paper lining, "WM. SHEW / MINIATURE CASE MAKER, / AND DEALER IN / Daguerreotype Materials / 123 Washington Street, / BOSTON"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1844-50 (Box 14, Folder 131)
        Sixth-plate daguerreotype; scotch-tape seal
    - Spooner Brothers
      Springfield
      - Framed portrait with overpaint, possibly originally a salt paper print of a woman, circa 1856-60 (Box 47, Folder 132)
        Wall frame with whole-plate size brass mat insert
  - MISSOURI PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Fitzgibbon, John H. (1819-1882)
      St. Louis
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a young man, circa 1846-50 (Box 14, Folder 133)
        Full papier-mache case; imprint on velvet pad, "FITZGIBBON / ARTIST. ST. LOUIS"
        Volume on a table in image, "Excelsior Annual / Pupil's Gift"
    - Long, Enoch
      - Tintype in a case, of a man in military uniform, circa 1860 (Box 14, Folder 134)
        Full leather case; imprint on velvet pad, "E. LONG / ARTIST / ST. LOUIS, MO"
    - Outley, John J.
      - Ambrotype in a case, of two women, 1859 Oct 13 (Box 14, Folder 135)
        Quarter-plate hand-tinted ambrotype; modern seal
        Full papier-mache case; imprint on velvet pad, "J.J. OUTLEY / ARTIST / 134 THIRD ST. / ST. LOUIS Mo"
        Ink inscription under image "Oct 13 / 1859"
      - Daguerreotype in a half case, of a man, 1856 Apr 3 (Box 14, Folder 136)
        Blindstamp in lower left corner of mat, "J.J. OUTLEY / ARTIST", and lower right corner of mat, "ST. LOUIS"
        Pencil inscription under image, "April 3rd, 1856"
  - NEW HAMPSHIRE PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Culver & Fellows
      Newport
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman posed with a United States flag, circa 1858 (Box 14, Folder 137)
        Ninth-plate clear-glass ambrotype; original seal
        Full leather case with scroll and leaf motif
        Printed paper card behind image, "From Culver & Fellows' Photographic Rooms, / NO. 2, NETTLETON & CO'S BLOCK / NEWPORT, N.H."
  - NEW YORK PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Beals, Albert J.
      New York
      - Two daguerreotypes in the same case, each depicting a woman, one young and the other elderly, 1846-54 (Box 14, Folder 138)
        Sixth-plate daguerreotypes, modern seals
        Blindstamp on each mat, "A.J. BEALS, 156 BROADWAY"
        Full double brown leather case
    - Cary, Charles H.
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, circa 1859-60 (Box 14, Folder 139)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; unsealed
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "CARY"; blindstamp lower right on mat, "371 / CANAL ST."
    - McIntyre, Sterling C.
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, 1850-51 (Box 14, Folder 140)
        Ninth-plate daguerreotype; original seal; perimeter tarnish.
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "MCINTYRE"; lower right, "663 BROADWAY NY"
        Full plain black leather case with morning glory motif on each corner of cover
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, 1850-51 (Box 15, Folder 141)
        Full black leather case with floral frame motif
    - Phillips, J. A.
      Fredonia, vicinity
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, identified as Judge Philip S. Cottle, 1857 Dec 21 (Box 15, Folder 142)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with iron sheeting backing; unsealed
        Blindstamp lower right on mat, "BY J.A. PHILLIPS"; blindstamp lower left on mat, "CUTTING & BOWDOIN / AMBROTYPE PATD JULY 4 & 11 1854"
        Full papier-mache case with geometric scroll motif
        Inscriptions on printed calling card of "Mr. O. O. Cottle", include "Judge Philip S. Cottle / Major in Civil War / Fredonia, N.Y. / Father of Mr. O.O. Cottle / Taken Dec. 21, 1857 / Born Oct. 29, 1805 / at Marthas Vinyard (sic.)"
    - Pine & Bells (George W. Pine)
      Troy
      - Asphaltum silhouette of a person of an undetermined gender on glass in a case missing its ambrotype plate, 1860-61 (Box 15, Folder 143)
        Sixth-plate silhouette of asphaltum; no seal
        Full papier-mache case with geometric scroll motif; blindstamp on velvet lining, "FROM/ PINE & BELLS / 394 / RIVER ST. / TROY, N.Y."
  - PENNSYLVANIA PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Broadbent, Samuel, 1810-1881
      Philadelphia
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman and man, circa 1857 (Box 15, Folder 144)
        Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with black paper backing; original seal
        Full leather case with geometric scroll motif
    - Gutekunst, Frederick (1831-1917)
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a family group including two girls, a woman, and man, 1856-60 (Box 15, Folder 145)
        Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum/varnish backing; unsealed
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "BY / GUTEKUNST"
        Full plain pigskin case
        Woman may be African American
    - Rehn, Isaac
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1854-59 (Box 15, Folder 146)
        Sixth-plate clear glass with asphaltum backing; sealed
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "AMBROTYPE / BY REHN"; blindstamp lower right on mat, "PATENT JULY / 4TH & 11TH 1854"
        Full leather case with tooled geometric line and ribbon design
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman and a girl, identified as Mrs. Hoopes and Susan J. Hoopes, 1854-59 (Box 15, Folder 147)
        Quarter-plate ambrotype; original seal
        Inscription on paper, "Mrs. Hoopes / & Susan J. Hoopes"
    - Shew, Myron (1824-1891)
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1850-59 (Box 15, Folder 148)
        Full leather case with Two Lilies motif (Rinhart #112); printed on paper lining, "MYRON SHEW, / DEALER IN / Daguerreotype Materials / No. 116 Chestnut Street, / PHILADELPHIA"
        Attributed to Myron Shew
  - VERMONT PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Merrill, James O.
      Brandon
      - Ambrotype with no case of a girl, circa 1860 (Box 15, Folder 149)
        Ninth-plate ambrotype; no seal
        Photographer's card attached, "JAMES O. MERRILL'S / AMBROTYPES / FOR / 25 CENTS, / ALSO THE / PATENT SEALED / AMBROTYPE / Put up for One Dollar / AT THE / DAGUERREAN GALLERY, / OVER SCOTT & BLISS' / Clothing Store, / BRANDON, VT."
  - GREAT BRITAIN PHOTOGRAPHERS
    - Hickling, J.
      Ramsgate or Margate, England
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a girl, 1859 (Box 15, Folder 150)
        Ninth-plate clear-glass hand-tinted ambrotype backed with brown velvet; no seal
        Full plain leather case
        Photographer's label in case behind image: "HICKLING / ARTIST, 25, HARBOUR STREET, / RAMSGATE AND / 157, High Street/ Margate."
    - Lenox, Isaac Shaw
      Bristol, England
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, 1858-63 (Box 16, Folder 151)
        Ninth-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo
        Full papier-mache case with geometric motif; photographer's calling card backing image, "I.S. LENOX / SCENIC AND PHOTOGRAPH[IC] / ARTIST, / AT HIS / PHOTOGRAPHIC GALLER[Y] / No. 2. BRIDGE STREET, / (Facing the Swan Hotel,) / BRISTOL, / WHERE YOU CAN HAVE TAKEN [in] / ANY WEATHER, / From 9 o' Clock till dusk. / A FIRST CLASS / MINIATURE PORTRAIT / This size, for ONE SHILLING"
    - Ritchie
      Edinburgh, Scotland
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1857 (Box 16, Folder 152)
        Ninth-plate ruby-glass hand-tinted ambrotype; no seal
        Full plain maroon pigskin case; blindstamp on back of leather case, "115 PRINCES STREET. / RITCHIE / PHOTOGRAPHER / EDINB."
  - PHOTOGRAPHERS WITH UNIDENTIFIED LOCATIONS
    - Atkinson, S. J.
      - Ambrotype not in a case, of a girl, circa 1860 (Box 16, Folder 153)
        Photographer's card attached, "FROM THE / MAMMOTH / TRAVELING / AMBROTYPE SALOON / S.J. ATKINSON, / PROPRIETER"
    - Beardsley, B. C.
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1848-51 (Box 16, Folder 154)
        Full leather case with the Tea Rose motif (Rinhart #130)
        Letter-pressed strip label on glass, "B.C. BEARDSLEY, DAGUERREAN"
    - Hamilton
      - Daguerreotype in half a case, of a woman, 1850-55 (Box 16, Folder 155)
        Blindstamp lower left on mat, "Hamilton"
      - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1854 (Box 16, Folder 156)
        Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing and cloth cover
        Blindstamp on mat, lower left, "HAMILTON"
        Full leather case in scroll and grape motif
    - Marks
      - Daguerreotype in half case of a man, circa 1854 (Box 16, Folder 157)
        Blindstamp under image on mat, "MARKS"
    - Plumbe, John, Jr., 1809-1857
      Plumbe operated franchise studios in Boston, Massachusetts; Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; Salem, Massachusetts; Exeter, New Hampshire; Dubuque, Iowa; New York, New York; Albany, New York; Saratoga Springs, New York; Baltimore, Maryland; New Orleans, Louisiana; and Washington, District of Columbia
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1841-45 (Box 16, Folder 158)
        Blindstamp lower right, "PLUMBE"
        Full leather case with variant of the Grecian Urn motif (Rinhart #140)
    - Whitehurst, Jesse Harrison (1819-1875)
      Whitehurst operated franchise studios in New York, New York; Baltimore, Maryland; Richmond, Virginia; Norfolk, Virginia; Petersburg, Virginia; and Lynchburg, Virginia
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, circa 1855-56 (Box 16, Folder 159)
        Blindstamp on mat, "WHITEHURST"
        Full pig-skin case (Rinhart #41); imprint on velvet pad of case, "J.H. WHITEHURST GALLERIES / NEW-YORK / BALTIMORE / RICHMOND / NORFOLK / PETERSBURG / & LYNCHBURG"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1851-56 (Box 16, Folder 160)
        Full leather case with Maiden with Cornucopia motif (Rinhart #163); imprint on velvet pad of case, "J.H. WHITEHURST GALLERIES / NEW-YORK / BALTIMORE / RICHMOND / NORFOLK / PETERSBURG / AND / LYNCHBURG"
      - Daguerreotype in a case, of a woman, circa 1855-56 (Box 17, Folder 161)
        Full brown leather case with Bird and Snake motif (Rinhart #96); imprint on velvet pad of case, "J.H. WHITEHURST GALLERIES / NEW-YORK / WASHINGTON D.C. / BALTIMORE / RICHMOND / NORFOLK / PETERSBURG / & LYNCHBURG"
- Identified Subjects by Unidentified Photographers, 1850-60; Series II; (26 items)
  Series II, Identified Subjects by Unidentified Photographers is arranged alphabetically by the surname or corporate name of the subject.
  - Alviso, Perlata, and Vallejo families
    - Ambrotype in a case, of five women, identified as members of the Peralta family, circa 1855 (Box 17, Folder 162)
      Oakland, California
      Attributed to William Shew
      Half-plate clear-glass hand-tinted ambrotype with brown velvet backing; original seal
      Full brown leather case with jeweled medallion with heart-shaped scrolls
    - Ambrotype with a horizontal orientation in a half case, of an exterior group portrait of a girl, a boy, three women, and three men, identified as members of the Peralta family, circa 1855-59 (Box 17, Folder 163)
      Half-plate clear-glass ambrotype with blackened metal plate that has been removed; note transfer of image to metal plate.
    - Tintype not in a case, of a woman and man, possibly of the Alviso, Perlata, or Vallejo families, circa 1860 (Box 17, Folder 164)
      Unidentified location, California
      Sixth-plate tintype
    - Tintype not in a case, of two women, identified as members of the Valentin Alviso family, circa 1860 (Box 17, Folder 165)
      Sixth-plate tintype, underdeveloped image
      Inscription on the paper affixed to back of item, "[indecipherable] ALVISO"
    - Tintype not in a case, of two women, identified as members of the Valentin Alviso family, circa 1860 (Box 17, Folder 166)
      Quarter-plate tintype
      Inscription on paper affixed to back of item, "V. ALVISO / Valentin Alviso family"
    - Tintype in a case, of a man, identified as Plutarco Jose Vallejo, circa 1860 (Box 17, Folder 167)
      Ninth-plate tintype
      Inscription on label in the case, "Plutarco / Jose Vallejo / son of Jose de / Jesus Vallejo"
    - Ambrotype in a case, of a woman, identified as a member of the Perlata and Vallejo families, circa 1860 (Box 17, Folder 168)
      Ninth-plate clear-glass ambrotype with asphaltum backing; no seal
      Identified as probably the woman posed second from right in Item 163
  - Amy, George
    - Daguerreotype in a case, of a man, wearing fraternal clothing, identified as George Amy, circa 1854 (Box 17, Folder 169)
      Marysville, California
      Half-plate daguerreotype
      Identification based on communication by Peter Palmquist with seller of the item at time of purchase, 1974
  - Anderson, C. A.
    - Ambrotype in a half case if a man, identified as C. A. Anderson, 1859 Sep 15 (Box 17, Folder 170)
      Sixth-plate ruby-glass ambrotype; no seal
      Pencil inscription on paper lining of case, "Sep 15th 1859 / Miss Irie A. Vansant / TRENTON [New Jersey] / When present hours seem / dark! Tis sweet to turn our thoughts from things of woe! / And think of one dear one / you know! You know. / C. A. Anderson. PROFESSOR / Taken Marysville, Ca."
  - Brown, C. D., and F. M. Failing
    - Ambrotype in a half case, of two men, identified as C. D. Brown and F. M. Failing, 1857 Jan-Feb (Box 18, Folder 171)
      Sacramento, California
      Pencil inscription on paper lining of case behind image, "F. M. Failing & / C. D. Brown were made / Masons January & / February 1857 / United we stand / divided we fall."
  - Cammerer, Eugene
    - Wet collodion process on leather with no case of a man, identified as Eugene Cammerer, circa 1856 (Box 18, Folder 172)
      Ink inscription on verso, "Uncle / Eugene Cammerer"
  - Carl, Ed[ward?]
    - Tintype in a case, of a boy, identified as Edward Carl, wearing a man's top hat and boots, 1865 Apr (Box 18, Folder 173)
      Middleville, probably in Michigan, New Jersey, or New York
      Full brown leather case with birds at fountain motif; mismatched cover and back of case
      Inscription on paper lining of case, "Eddie Carl / Middleville / April 1865"
  - Corning, Etta
    - Tintype in a case, of a woman holding a book, identified as Etta Corning, circa 1860 (Box 18, Folder 174)
      Unidentified location
      Sixth-plate tintype; no seal
      Inscription on paper in the case, "Etta Corning"
  - Dana, William Goodwin
    - Tintype not in a case, of a man, identified as William Goodwin Dana (1797-1858), circa 1856-58 (Box 18, Folder 175)
      Printed calling card accompanies the tintype, "Miss Adelina Dana"; probably the card of Adelina (Ellen) Dana (1873-1893), the granddaughter of William Goodwin Dana
      William Goodwin Dana was a merchant ship captain and settled in Santa Barbara, California, in 1825. In 1828, he married Maria Josefa Carrillo, the eldest daughter of Don Carlos Antonio Carrillo, who was later provisional governor of California. In 1835, Dana became a citizen of Mexico and Captain of the Port at Santa Barbara. In 1836 he was Alcade of Santa Barbara. In 1839, Dana moved to a Mexican land grant in Nipomo, California, and built the Dana Adobe
  - Drummond family
    - Daguerreotype with a horizontal orientation in a case, of a woman, identified as Jane Drummond, and an unidentified man, circa 1851 (Box 18, Folder 176)
      San Francisco vicinity, California
      Full leather case with stippled central medallion
      Inscription on lining of case, "Mrs. Jane Drummond / Died April 9, 1859"
    - Tintype not in a case, of a woman, identified as a member of the Drummond family, circa 1860 (Box 18, Folder 177)
      Inscription on note with item, "Drummond / family / Bay Area"
  - Hartwell, Albert
    - Ambrotype in a case, of a man holding a violin, identified as Albert Hartwell, circa 1856 (Box 18, Folder 178)
      Chico, California
      Sixth-plate clear-glass ambrotype in relievo; no seal
      Full leather case with laurel wreath around urn motif
      Inscription on cloth pad of case, "Albert Hartwell / Chico, CA", inscription on paper lining, "Wife, Fannie / [indecipherable]"
  - Lid, A. S.
    - Wet collodion process on leather in case of a man, identified as A. S. Lid, circa 1860 (Box 18, Folder 179)
      Ninth-plate wet collodion process on leather
      Inscription on paper lining under image, "Me / A. S. Lid"
  - Merriam, Jennie
    - Daguerreotype with case of a woman, identified as Jennie Merriam, circa 1850-60 (Box 18, Folder 180)
      Unidentified location, New York
      Sixth-plate daguerreotype; mat vignette to oval between ninth-plate and sixteenth-plate; original seal
      Full case with a black lacquer mother-of-pearl inlay cover and a brown leather back with gold pattern imprint
      Inscription on paper accompanying item, "Aunt Jennie Merriam"; inscription on verso of paper in different hand, "Died of Tuberculosis / at 19 / New York State"
  - Merrill, Selah (1837-1909)
    - Ambrotype in a case, of a man, identified as Selah Merrill, 1861 Feb 4 (Box 19, Folder 181)
      New Haven, Connecticut
      Full plain leather case with gold scrolling
      Inscription on velvet pad of case, "Seleh Merrill / 1861", and inscription on slip of paper, "Taken at N. Haven / Ct., Feb. 4th 1861"
      Selah Merrill was a clergyman, Hebraist, and U.S. Consul in Jerusalem (1882-1886)